## **EFE BUYURAN**

Front-End Developer



+90 (532) 474 5446 efebuyuran@gmail.com efebuyuran.com

## Hello!

I'm a **Sn. Front-End Developer** from **Istanbul with 8 years of experience**, specializing in building modern user interfaces by **React & TypeScript** with a strong emphasis on aesthetics.

Having worked across products used by millions of people, I'm looking to utilize this experience to create new and exciting apps. I've worked for companies such as **Riot Games**, Spinmatic Entertainment, Hyundai, and Huawei. I'm only considering **remote** options at the present.

I believe in honesty, teamwork, and positivity for an efficient work environment. While being **open to feedback**, **accepting responsibility**, and **attention to detail** are my approach to professional work.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**GrubTech** - Software Engineer Remote ~ Feb. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Worked on Cloud Kitchen solutions.

## Riot Games - Software Engineer

Istanbul ~ March 2019 - Jul. 2021

- Worked on integrating RTL support for League of Legends Client Application. Since this was new to Riot, our team took the initiative to lead RTL support for other Riot services including, Riot Client, Player support hub, and Login services using Javascript, Stylus, and RTLCSS plugin.
- Created scalable Single Page Applications to promote in-game store merchandise on League of Legends Client Hub using React, TypeScript and Styled Components.
- Integrated an independent streamer to lolesports.com with React.
- Rebranded LoL Cafe B2B web application (lolcafe.tr.leagueoflegends.com). I was merely responsible for Front-End development but ended up contributing to the design as well.
- Supervised development for User Generated Content competition app created with React.

## Spinmatic Entertainment - Front-End Developer

Istanbul ~ Nov. 2017 - Mar. 2019

- Worked on the development of a pre-designed mobile app that supports multiple slot games, took responsibility, and delivered a new UX-friendly design with better features using Adobe Tools, React and Redux and SASS.
- Setup a paytable app to work inside slot games which supported manual theming for different game designs.

## The King Content Creative Agency - Front-End Developer

Istanbul ~ Apr. 2016 - Nov. 2017

- Created Single Page Applications for marketing promotions of Hyundai, Huawei, and Aygaz.
- Built websites for small businesses.
- Made animated banner ads with HTML5 & CSS.

## N'oluyo - Front-End Developer

Istanbul ~ Sep - Dec 2015

- Maintained an existing web platform, fixed bugs, provided UX solutions, implemented new features.

# **1V1Y** - Jnr. Graphic Designer Istanbul ~ Feb - Jul 2015

- I was responsible from providing page designs for an online magazine that features fashion elements and inspirations.

#### FRONT-END SKILLS

#### HTML 5

#### CSS

- SASS
- Stylus
- Styled components

#### JavaScript

- ES6
- TypeScript
- React, Redux
- Restful APIs, GraphQL
- Mocha, Chai, Sinon

#### **Build Automation**

- NPM & NVM
- Gulp
- Webpack

#### Mobile Development

- Dart & Flutter

#### Other

- Lighthouse
- Cross-Browser & Platform Compatibility

#### UI & UX

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Figma
- Responsive Design
- CSS Animations
- Dynamic SVG
- RightToLeft Interfaces

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Istanbul Commerce University**

Visual Communication 2009 - 2015

#### Yelkikanat And. Meslek Lisesi

Vocational High School, Computer 2004 - 2009

#### **İSTEK Acıbadem College**

Middle School 2000 - 2004

#### Eyüboğlu College

Primary Education

1995 - 2000

## **LANGUAGES**

Turkish is my native language. I can read, write, and speak fluently in English.

#### **HOBBIES**

I love riding my motorcycle and I'm very interested discussing ethics and philosophy.